Hello.
In this next lecture, we're going to go over how to give a health bar to our enemy character so we
can visually see how much help it has when we damage them.
To get started, I want us to create a new folder and just call it widget blueprints.
Once you've done this, head inside this folder and create another folder and just call it images.
Once you've done this really close on your engine and attach in the lecture of this course, I'm going
to make sure to include these two images.
Just drag them inside of this folder.
Once you've done that, select both of the images right click and go through fractions and apply paper
to texture settings.
We're now ready to create an enemy health bar.
We're going to create it in something called a Widget Blueprint, which allows us to display user interfaces
inside of Unreal Engine.
So to create one, just right click and go user interface, then set widget blueprint.
So use a widget and call this enemy helper underscore widget blueprint.
We then want to double click and head inside here.
And currently it's blank on the palette.
You want to look for canvas panel.
So no, look, canvas.
Just select it and drag it inside of this enemy health widget blueprint.
You'll be able to see this little grid.
Inside of this grid is where we're going to customize our health bar.
Go back to the palette and look for progress for.
Just dragons like that and move it somewhere into the middle of your screen.
Then just go anchor and select this middle one.
And this will just ensure when we display the health bar, it's going to appear in the center of the
screen.
Next, I want you to go to our test progress.
Currently, the percent is zero.
This goes from a value of 0 to 1.
And as I increase it, this bar is going to fill up.
We can also change how it builds up.
So if I just select this and go right to left, we can make this bar fill up from the right to left
or from the center.
But for now, let's just set left or right.
But I just wanted to show you that in case you wanted to customize it next, in order to customize our
health bar, because the default one looks kind of boring.
Go over to where it says style.
Then go to background image.
And on the background image, I want you to look for the enemy health bar.
Sorry.
I want you to look for the health bar.
This one.
The health bar.
Empty.
And under draw as just like image.
Then I want you to go to feel image and select the enemy Health ball.
And then I wanted to go to draw ads and select image.
Now I scroll down and I go to my present.
It's going to flip between those two images.
So that's why we imported them.
If you had your own custom health bar, you could use it there.
I'm just going to adjust the size of this as it looks a bit stretch so when we get a bit thicker.
So the idea here is we're going to use this progress bar to represent the health of our enemy.
And when our enemy has full health, it's going to be at one.
And when our enemy has no health, then it's going to suddenly deteriorate and look like this.